hesaa.org 2016-03-23

# 

                                                                                                              Rev. 10/2/2015
FACTS                 WHAT DOES: NJ Higher Education Student Assistance Authority (“HESAA”)
                      DO WITH YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION?
Why?                 Financial companies choose how they share your personal information. Federal law gives
                     consumers the right to limit some but not all sharing. Federal law also requires us to tell you
                     how we collect, share, and protect your personal information. Please read this notice carefully to
                     understand what we do.
What?                The types of personal information we collect and share depend on the product or service you
                     have with us. This information can include:
                        Social Security number, income and assets
                        Account balances and payment history
                        Account transactions, credit scores and credit history
                     When you are no longer our customer, we continue to share your information as described in this
                     notice.
How?                 All ﬁnancial companies need to share customers’ personal information to run their everyday
                     business. In the section below, we list the reasons ﬁnancial companies can share their
                     customers’ personal information; the reasons HESAA chooses to share; and whether you
                     can limit this sharing.
Reasons we can share your personal information                 Does HESAA share?            Can you limit this sharing?
For our everyday business purposes—
such as to process your transactions, maintain
your account(s), respond to court orders and legal                       YES                             No
investigations, or report to credit bureaus
For our marketing purposes—                                              YES                             No
to offer our products and services to you
For joint marketing with other ﬁnancial companies                        No                       We Don’t Share
For our afﬁliates’ everyday business purposes—                           YES                             No
information about your transactions and experiences
For our afﬁliates’ everyday business purposes—                           No                       We Don’t Share
information about your creditworthiness
For nonafﬁliates to market to you                                        No                       We Don’t Share
Questions?             Call (609) 584-4480 or go to www.hesaa.org

Page 2
Who we are
                                 This Privacy Notice is being provided by the State of New Jersey Higher
Who is providing this notice?    Education Student Assistance Authority (“HESAA”).
What we do
How does HESAA                    To protect your personal information from unauthorized access
protect my personal information?  and use, we use security measures that comply with federal law.
                                  These measures include computer safeguards and secured ﬁles
                                  and buildings.
How does HESAA                    We collect your personal information, for example, when you:
collect my personal information?
                                     Apply for a loan or give us your contact information
                                     Open an account or pay your bills
                                   Provide employment information
                                  We also collect your personal information from others, such as credit
                                  bureaus, affiliates, or other companies.
Why can’t I limit all sharing?    Federal law gives you the right to limit only:
                                      sharing for affiliates’ everyday business purposes—information
                                       about your creditworthiness
                                      affiliates from using your information to market to you
                                      sharing for nonafﬁliates to market to you
                                  State laws and individual companies may give you additional rights to
                                  limit sharing.
Deﬁnitions
Afﬁliates                         Companies related by common ownership or control. They can be
                                  ﬁnancial and nonﬁnancial companies.
                                     Our affiliates include other State of New Jersey government agencies,
                                  authorities, boards and commissions.
Nonafﬁliates                      Companies not related by common ownership or control. They can be
                                  ﬁnancial and nonﬁnancial companies.
                                     HESAA does not share with nonaffiliates so they can market to you.
Joint marketing                   A formal agreement between nonaffiliated ﬁnancial companies that
                                  together market ﬁnancial products or services to you.
                                     HESAA doesn't jointly market.
Other important information
